I think the majority of people online
that are telling you
that you should try and
get rich are wrong.
Because although I do very well,
I wouldn't say I'm that rich.
But
when it comes to my lifestyle,
I would say I am.
This is the beach that I live on,
and this is where I walk my dog every
morning.
And here's my car.
So many people now live in this world
where they think they need
to be millionaires on paper.
But for years,
I didn't have crazy amounts of money to
my name, but I had an incredible life.
The thing that you really want is freedom.
And out of all the people
that have created it,
I'm probably the laziest and the
least hardworking of them all. And
that should inspire you, because rewind
10 years, yeah, I was a personal trainer,
but I was also selling coke and MD to
people that I shouldn't have been.
Don't know whether or not to keep that in.
Yeah, keep it in the edit.
I've been a face-to-face personal trainer.
I've done door-to-door sales.
I've done so many crap jobs.
And I never really stuck with any of them
because I don't really like working that
hard. But over the last five, 10 years,
I've created a set of systems, a framework
that you can follow,
and it means you don't have to work
that hard, and you get
better results than everyone else.
I'll put the windows up because
that titanium exhaust
is going to make some noise.
Everything about my life is lazy.
I live right on the beach,
so I don't have to
travel to go anywhere. My office
is less than a kilometer away because I
don't want
to have to commute.
There's no staff in there, because to me,
managing staff
sounds like work.
I'd much rather run a really lean team.
And if you want to know the truth,
talking of laziness, I haven't even really
prepared today's video. But that's okay,
because I know exactly what I'm going to
talk about.
A lot of business gurus will tell you
about how they're making millions
of dollars from the business
that they have that teaches people how to
make
millions of dollars.
But I think first of all,
I'll show you how I've made millions
of dollars in an unsexy business.
A business where paid ads haven't really
worked.
A business that's been a slog for eight
years.
But it's the business
that bought my house,
paid for me to travel the world, and
allowed me to accomplish one thing
that I've always kind of taken for
granted.
I haven't had to go to work in eight
years. This is work.
It's 11:23 in the morning.
I'll do this video, go home.
I'm definitely having a nap today.
I'm going to wake up from my nap,
have a cup of coffee, and myself,
my fiancée, and
my son,
I think we're going to go to the beach
because it's 37 degrees.
If every component of my business isn't on
easy mode, I don't want to know about
it. I don't know what you're thinking.
Why do you not have the GT3 RS?
Well,
this is very important because I carry my
stuff in there, and the GT3 RS
doesn't have that. And
if you really want to see the levels of
laziness, when I get
to the office, everything is set up
and ready to go. So let's get into it.
Okay, let's get lazy. All right.
First bit of work I'm willing to do
is I'm going
to upload these videos from the DJI.
That is it.
That's all the admin I'm doing for today.
Going to send that to Declan.
Young Declan. First part of the vid.
Tell Anna. Okay.
Right.
Probably should start with an appeal to
authority.
Pretty much in any video,
you don't care about me,
but you should care about
yourself.
And the only reason you would care about
what I've done is so you can
apply it to you. That is how this works.
Any transformative thing you're doing,
even if you are a builder and you're
renovating a bathroom, the before
and after of the bathroom isn't because
they care
about that person's bathroom, it's
that they care about their own bathroom.
And if you can show them
that transformative process,
they can apply it to
themselves. Now,
not all payments come through this,
but as you can see here,
$16.6 million. Now, that is Australian.
Okay, 11.1 million. What's that a month
over eight years?
And although $11 million may not seem like
a huge
deal,
this is very much what I just call a
lifestyle business.
It's me and my business partner, James,
and we've never had more than nine staff.
$115,000 per month, $3,800 per day, and
over eight years. It's pretty good.
A lot of people burn out before then.
Okay,
so something quite important to realize
here is if you've been listening to
any of my most recent videos,
I tear everything into the four-stage 4S's
system.
We go socials, squeeze, sell, scale.
So a lot of you guys have probably seen
some of my fitness content online.
And if you were to ask me what the main
priority of all of that content out over
the years was, it
was to get email addresses.
Socials, I've got 1.8 million on TikTok,
1.1 million on Facebook, 1.4
million on Instagram,
about 450,000 on YouTube.
But if you said to me,
you get to pick keeping your email list
or keeping your
socials, I would say take those socials.
So you've got all the years of work
that I've done to get people's contact
information.
Might as well show you one of the ways
that we get it.
So one of the squeezes here
is just a macro calculator
that we built in.
Now, in 2026,
is this really going to benefit your
business that much?
Not really, but it's a tool
that people can use,
and it gets us email addresses.
So if you were someone that
was messaging people in their DMs,
or you're someone
that's doing sales calls,
or you're someone that's doing what I
would consider
high-effort activities,
you'd make me shudder at the thought of
it.
So instead here, I have an offer
that I want to send.
I'm going to do it the laziest way
possible.
Going to write an email marketing email.
So sender, me.
Recipients, let's go daily emails,
434,145. Now, think for a second. I'm a
lazy person. I don't work that hard.
Over the years,
I've just been collecting emails on the
side so that I can send
people an offer. To me,
the idea of being able to talk to 400,000
people at the
same time is just far more exciting than
anything else.
So we're just going to skip a step here
where we've gone from squeeze.
This is the sell.
But the fourth element being scale
is why I have this.
There's never a world where you could do
thousands and thousands of sales calls on
a given day, even if it
was to help conversions.
And like I say, people I know that
are doing sales calls probably make more
money
than me. But I don't want the effort.
I don't want a sales team.
I don't want any of that hustle.
I just want to promote my offer, and
if people
want it, they want it. Okay. Let me think,
because we sit here and we kind of think
to ourselves,
what would make a good email? Hmm.
Sometimes I go to my Facebook memories
because ultimately we want to try
and divulge some kind of story to people.
We spoke about the transformative story
before. Hmm, let's have a look.
Might have to go to the personal Facebook.
Oh, here we go.
There's a video here of me doing a
backflip. I reckon we can cook with this.
Let's give it a go.
On my Facebook memories today,
I saw a video of myself
11 years ago going to a trampoline park.
I remember it well because Laura,
one of my clients, turned up to the gym
with a face like a slapped ass.
I asked her what's up.
She replied honestly saying she couldn't
be arsed to train today.
So I said,
"Let's go to a trampoline park." One had
opened nearby.
I said,
"I'll keep the money for the session,
but I'll pay our
entry." She agreed. This is a true story,
by the way.
In the video I saw this morning,
I'm doing a backflip.
And I thought to myself, well,
how times change.
Because nowadays, I have
To brace and hold my knees when I sneeze.
I am pretty sure I pulled a muscle in my
neck
sleeping wrong the other day,
and I get a hangover from a
non-alcoholic beer.
To those of you youngsters reading
this, whatever they say about aging,
it's worse. Much worse.
So I'm going to like, bit of a story,
bit of relatability,
because I think people
go, "Yeah, do you know what?
Getting old sucks." I hate to be the
bearer of bad news,
but you only have a finite
amount of workouts left in you before your
body gives up.
The same way that every human being has
only a certain
capacity of work in their lifetime.
The good news is eating well,
being in shape, and training hard actually
improves the amount of sessions
and time you have
left training. Ten years ago,
I could do a backflip,
so in 10 years' time,
I'll probably be one hay fever sneezing
fit
away from slipping a disc.
If you have your shit in
order,
absolutely don't join my six-month
challenge.
But if you want to get on top of losing
weight, becoming stronger,
building habits your body will thank you
about in 10
years,
then there's no better time to enroll to
my top five
challenge. More information here. Now,
where is that link?
Where is that link? Here we go. Give
that a little underline, bit of bold.
Then down here, "Don't forget,
one month money-back guarantee.
All workouts and check-ins included.
Five lucky buggers coming to Dubai.
All expenses." Now what I'll do
is for these, maybe we go
italic. For these, I reckon we go bold,
bold, italic.
Now we're going to center align it.
Just that's the way I like to do my
emails.
Let's go back up to the top.
Maybe we could put a little break here.
Maybe we underline that bad boy. Gosh.
Okay, one last thing to do.
Double-check. Look at that. [chuckles]
If you're reading this,
I forgot to write a
subject line. I'll never backflip again.
Maybe a little gymnastics.
Yeah, that'll do. Test your email. Yes.
When sending an email to 400,000 people,
it's often a good idea to check
your link,
because otherwise it's not good.
Here we go. I'll never backflip again.
See what it looks like from their angle.
Click of the link. Cool.
Yeah, sounds amazing.
Let me know what you would like me to
order, and I shall
get it on the way home. Now,
some of you might have thought that
was a voice note,
and I hate voice notes. It wasn't. It
was dictate.
And if any of you out there,
if you're going to use your voice to send
a message,
just dictate. All right? Just dictate.
Be respectful. Okay, so look at that.
That's it. I'm going to send that.
It's going to go to 434,000 people,
and out of them,
we'll get some people joining the
challenge.
Now, think of it this way.
All the hundreds and thousands of people
that don't
buy, I don't get any feedback about.
I only get feedback of the people
that buy.
There was also a PS at the bottom to get
people to listen to the podcast.
And some people will go listen to the
podcast,
and they'll go back up in the funnel
to socials.
But then eventually they'll get squeezed
maybe in a different funnel
for a different business, who knows?
Then the other place they can go to from
there is to buy Nutonic.
So again, they've come into that socials,
squeeze.
We're in the sell phase, and even
if we're not selling JSA,
they're now selling
Nutonic. Then the scalability of that
is whether there's 400, 4,000
or 400,000 people,
my work remains the same.
Now, you will notice
that I've been quite proactive on my main
Instagram, firing
out different videos recently to do with
fitness, even though I don't talk about
fitness that much.
It's because I wanted more fresh leads on
that list so I can hit
them to promote the offer for James
Academy.
Now,
what if I was to tell you that's my work
for that business done for today?
Done. That was it.
Because now the fourth S in
that position is scale,
and I've scaled the business
and hired amazing coaches
that rotate the programs for
me.
Because any of you out there operating a
business or a
personal brand,
eventually you do want to build it to run
without you.
It's just the way it is. So then
if we think about the socials for
James Smith Business Mentorship,
I've got a video going out at 6:00 p.m.
tonight or tomorrow morning actually,
maybe your evening, about why AI is making
you dumber.
Got a video currently out there now.
As far as socials as well,
we can also look at RevTrack to look at
some of the
money that we're making from these videos.
See here, $22,000 from that video,
20,000 from that one, 11,000 from
this one. It's bloody wonderful.
You can see all the sales coming in from
different
products. And what I like here
is from a socials aspect of this business,
I
made these videos ages ago, months.
That one, 10th of March, 2025,
and look at all
these sales. Ding, ding, ding, ding, ding,
ding, ding. Why?
Because it's lazy and I like being lazy.
I create videos just like this video right
now.
Even now, I'm going to say to you,
there's actually a link in the description
to
this video where I'll offer you an offer.
So I'll show you.
The other day, I did a live stream,
one hour fifty-one, 3,000 people have
watched, and in it there
was a special offer.
Pretty sure we saved like $1,000.
I'm going to put
that offer in this video
and I'm going to keep it there until we
get 100 purchases. So for any of you
that want to save $1,000, you
can with that link. But once we hit 100,
I'm going to take it offline and you'll
just get the old website again.
So from a social standpoint, for me,
that was a bit
of work. I had to be live for two hours.
But let's have a look at some of these
analytics for a second.
And again,
I'm going to take you through the four
S's. Social, squeeze, sell.
First of all,
to get 91 subscribers from a live stream,
that's pretty good.
500 messages during, and concurrently,
we had what?
480 people watching.
So although I had to give two hours of my
time,
we on average had 480 people watching.
So if I said to you,
"Would you go do an event with 500
attendees?" You'd be like,
"Yeah,
of course." You'd probably fly to another
country to do it.
So the live stream for me
is such a great way to do it.
So you get all of those viewers,
then the best thing
is you can then leave the
video evergreen after.
So you'll notice
that this other live stream here
that I did
the other day, 10,000 views, which
is insane.
Average for that one was 634 people,
858 at its
peak. But then let's look at that.
The amount of views,
the amount of people that
have been watching that,
the amount of engagement, that
is absolutely bloody
bonkers. Now,
here's quite an interesting one for you.
You may have noticed
that I've actually been using,
because I know this video
converts so well and we're still at
that socials part of this lazy way to
generate
a business. Because I know
that this video is converting people into
business so
well,
I then created other YouTube videos
and made it the end card.
So yeah,
you'll notice that's where you're getting
some of the traffic from, which
is just bloody marvelous.
So from a social standpoint, we're here.
Now if we look down to the next part of
that component being squeeze, getting
people's data,
I ran signups for both those live streams.
So those live streams
are invaluable because they're also going
to work evergreen.
And what I mean when I say evergreen
is this.
If we go to videos here
and we click on the most popular video,
let's go on this
one. If we look at the analytics,
I love pointing out this video for
129 days. So three, six, nine, 12, four
months, nothing, and then phew.
Takes off. Even in the last 48 hours,
658 views.
This was posted over a year ago. One year,
17 hours, still getting 300 views a day.
So when it comes to having a lazy way to
make money, this is still generating
purchases, keep in mind.
I posted something a year ago
and it's still making me
money. Do you know how amazing that is?
Love that.
And basically, the premise is here.
This is everything I'm going to teach you
in my mentorship.
So now we have the sale component,
which is why I told you there's an offer
for 100
of you. Let's look at the scale.
So first of all, this should work,
actually. Today,
6.7. Oh, 6.9 Gs. Seven Gs.
Come on. Seven Gs for the day.
Maybe I do get the GT3 RS.
This month, what are we at? Eighth of Jan.
Gs for Jan. Eighth of Jan. Come on.
This could be a fucking
300K month. I'm only joking.
The money makes me miserable.
But remember what I said before,
maybe I'm contradicting myself because
that is
rich figures,
and the last time I did a video, I
was at what? 3.9 mil.
Been in business 25 months. I made
$4.438802 million US dollars. What is
that a day?
I'm not doing this to show off.
Appeal to authority again.
I'm proving to you
that this system works because I use these
systems
to teach you the systems. If
that makes sense.
I teach you to run Instagram channels,
do social media and email marketing.
It's exactly what I use
and it generates me pretty good.
5.8K a day.
And think of it this way. I'm so lazy,
but I can run multiple
businesses in a day because you just
watched me generate all the rev I need for
one business, the JSA.
You're now watching me in real time do it
again for
another business.
But I'm pretty delighted with that.
I'm not going to lie to you.
I'll take that.
I have no idea where that's coming from.
Okay, so the sell component of that
is actually this video.
You are right in the middle of a sales
storm.
I could write an email to you,
but instead I'm going to put it there.
But if I did want your email address,
let me show you as well.
If you go to my channel,
you'll notice there's loads of links here.
And actually, the majority of my videos,
so if you look down here, I have all the
different ways that you can enter
that squeeze. Socials, squeeze.
There's so many links there.
I've got seven different offers.
Four of them are free
and three of them are paid.
And for any of you watching this video,
if you're not going to take me up and join
the mentorship, save $1,000, there's that.
There's also something else I want to show
you.
I haven't publicly, well, I did publicly,
I put it on my story yesterday.
If you do take me up on the offer to join
my mentorship, basically you pay a
one-off fee, you're in for life.
So the people that joined for $800 US are
still in there. And
when we get into Mentorship 2.0,
these courses weren't all
here. I build them as we go along. Now,
this Black Belt Content Mastery course is
getting refilmed,
but I added this one yesterday.
It's the silver play button.
It's everything you need to get one of
those.
And it's a pretty full on course. And
again,
I'm giving you the opportunity to get this
as part of the mentorship with
the discount that's currently in the
description.
Now, once you watch these,
you get questions.
Let's say you watch Lead Magnet Mastery.
You might have a question about lead
magnets.
It's where you come to the Discord.
And for instance,
here we're going through some title
and thumbnails.
Even right now, I'm showing you
that yesterday's thumbnail,
I ideated from these
guys. So I seen the fellas
and this thumbnail trend working, made my
own.
I'll probably watch those on the basis of
my Instagram feed to people
interviews as a GP.
Just feels a bit wanky to put it sort
front.
You can always put
that in the introduction.
So what you're watching now as well
is the scale aspect, I suppose,
because I've
already sold to these people. Now,
we're helping Lynette here with her
thumbnails and this person with red text
is Ollie.
Ollie is actually my YouTube strategist,
and he helps other channels in
here in the Discord.
Even Ollie here in our WhatsApp is
giving me different ideas for YouTube of
what he thinks is going to work.
So
my own YouTube strategist
is in here helping people.
Airbnb hosts can four times revenue during
2026 World Cup.
Yeah, I agree with Adam here.
I think we need a how-to or so.
That's good because Adam just said
that as well. Give him a little...
Or we could even go how B&B hosts will
4X their revenue this World Cup. Sorry,
I can't.
Once I see a thread,
I've got to get into it.
And again, as you can see,
some of these threads I've done stuff
with, other
threads I haven't. And as I scale this,
I'm just going to bring in more experts.
So like you see there,
you see me making 100 grand in a
week. Part of me thinks just take it all,
James. Just take it and run with it.
But then I think probably should hire
another full-time person to be in there.
Now, I'm not going to lie to you.
I like spending time in here every
day.
It's kind of where I scaled in the other
business, but not in this one because
I need a finger on the pulse of what's
working for people and what isn't.
The other people are in there to support.
They get their own channels.
Like Cam is a marketing genius
and he's helped fitness businesses in
particular grow their brands online.
But this isn't one of my lazy things.
The reason I'm in here
is it really helps me with ideation for
content online.
So selfishly,
I spend a lot of time in here because it
is just fantastic for having
back and forth with people so that
when I come to the office here,
I have so much
to talk about. Now,
any business experts watching this would
have so
many bits of advice they could give me to
make my business better.
But unfortunately,
the majority of them stem towards having
to do more.
And for me, I own a comfortable living.
I live on the beach.
I spend a lot of time with my partner
and son. I get to nap most days.
No one tells me what to do and that
is actually what I think the wealth is
that a lot of us are missing.
So many people out there might be earning
the same as
me, but they spend all day filming videos,
all day sales calls, all
day delivering to their clients.
I just don't want to do that
and I don't think my
clients want me to do
that for them either.
The reason I use a Discord as well,
some of you wondering, is because I'm lazy
and I don't want to get on the phone with
people.
The only interaction I'm going to have
with anyone today is that camera
and my son
and my fiancée.
And even though I could jump on calls for
five grand an hour doing
consultancy,
I don't want to because I'm lazy.
The reason I like the Discord as well
is I can service people
and help them so much
with their ideation without having to talk
to them, which again is preservation of
effort. Now,
if that resonates with you
and you want to build a world
and a business similar to mine,
I'm not the richest in the room.
I'm not the wealthiest person on YouTube.
I don't have a million pounds in my bank
account.
I do have a million Aussie dollars,
but technically it's in my mortgage.
Technically.
And I don't aspire to be the richest
person you know or the richest
person you follow.
But the one place I will always win the
wealth battle is
lifestyle.
Some people have more money than me.
They live in Dubai or London.
I win.
Some people have more money than me.
They live in a fucking apartment.
I live on the beach. I win.
Some people have bigger
and more successful podcasts
than me. I have a family
that I spend all my time with. I win.
I may not have the most money,
the most fame, the most notoriety,
or the most
pulling power online,
but I'm one of the wealthiest
when it comes to a combination
of what we should be going after in life.
If you want me to teach you exactly how I
do it, because it's not luck at
this point, right?
You don't run a business
that does 11 mil and then
trip up and do another one
that does four mil at the same time as
getting a drinks
brand to 20 mil valuation.
Either I'm so lucky I should be doing
scratch cards or
this system fucking works.
Let me have a look at that offer quick.
What are we fucking charging? What
are we fucking charging?
And I'll teach you how to make a sexy ass
landing page like this as well.
And the reason I prefer a landing page
is if you go through this with the link in
the description and it's not compelled you
to buy and you need a phone call, fuck
off and join someone else's because you're
going to be hard work already.
There we go. Two and a half Gs US dollar.
1,800 pound.
That's so cheap. That is too cheap.
If anything, 100 people, 1,800 pound.
I've had more expensive dinners.
That's abhorrent. Look,
that YouTube course
is worth more than 1,800 pounds,
let alone everything else.
The information there
is worth more than 1,800 pounds,
let alone everything else. At this stage,
it's going to seem like a hard sell, but
I don't give a fuck. I'm lazy as fuck.
I run big businesses.
I don't work that hard.
I have a dream life.
If you want to learn how to do the same,
join. If not, don't.
And remember that webinar
that I told you about that
if you watch it, you'll
probably end up buying from me?
If you're not going to click on the link
in the
description,
you might as well go check out
that webinar.
Remember how I showed you that I
was sending traffic to it because it was
converting people?
How to get leads to come to you in 2026.
All right.
I hope you lot have had a good day. Oh,
what's that? 5 minutes past 12.
I think I'm having the rest of the day
off. Why? Because I can. It's the Ashes.
It's 37 degrees outside
and I'm too lazy to do any more work for
today.
And please buy today so I can make it 100
grand for the week. That'd be nice.
I'm such a dickhead. Bye.